片名：北O特快
在多年前的一}Q夜Y
On Christmas Eve, many years ago...
我oo的躺在自己的床上
...I lay quietly in my bed.
我]有翻砀踩
I did not rustle the sheets.
我p慢的呼吸著
I breathed slowly and silently.
我正注意的著
只怕]K
I was listening for a sound
I was afraid I'd never hear.
}Q老人雪橇上的K
The ringing bells of Santa's sleigh.
好了，莎拉
F在水也喝^了
All right. All right, Sarah,
you had your water.
是不是乖乖上床睡X了啊？
Now let's get you upstairs
and into bed.
可是K可是K我K
But-- But-- But, l have to--
哥哥f}Q老人要w得比光快K
He said Santa would have to
fly faster than light...
才能在一晚上跑遍每人的家K
...to get to every house in one night.
And to hold everyone's presents...
而且如果他要送Y物o大家
那他的雪橇一定要比大船要大
...his sled would be bigger
than an ocean liner.
唉，那是哥哥在跟你_玩笑
他知道有}Q老人呀
Your brother said that? He was just
kidding you. He knows there's a Santa.
他f他不知道啊
他不知道有]有}Q老人
He said he wasn't sure.
He wasn't sure if Santa was for real.
然有}Q老人啊
不然怎N有}Q呢
Of course Santa is real.
He's as real as Christmas itself.
可是如果你不s快睡著
}Q老人是不淼泥
But he won't come until you're
sound asleep, young lady.
乖乖睡吧
Sweet dreams.
等你一睡著，}Q老人就
Santa will be here before you know it.
快c睡吧
So go to sleep.
（百公司的}Q老人T工了！）
（晚螅
（大lF）
（北O）
光ddKB不生蛋K
''Stark, barren.
一c生庖]有
Devoid of life.''
他已睡著了吧
He's gotta be asleep by now.
以前他老是整夜不肯睡
非要等}Q老人
He used to stay awake all night
waiting for Santa.
我想那些日子都已^去了吧
Think those days are just about over.
唉，如果真是@樱真人y^呢
That would be sad if that were true.
是啊，童年幻想Y束
Yeah, an end of the magic.
}Q快罚乖鹤
Merry Christmas, sweetheart.
他睡得真熟啊
See, he's out like a light.
我看就B特快火^也吵不醒他
An express train
wouldn't wake him up now.
童年幻想Y束？
''End of the magic''?
上樱
All aboard!
（北O特快）
你要上幔
Well? You coming?
去哪？
Where?
那用f，然是去北O呀！
Why, to the North Pole, of course.
@班就是北O特快
This is the Polar Express.
去北O？
The North Pole?
我懂了
l see.
你臀夷靡幌
Hold this, please.
xx
Thank you.
@是你幔
ls this you?
-ρ
-上面著，今年K
-Yeah.
-Well, it says here...
不跟百公司的}Q老人合照
不信o}Q老人
...no photo with a department-store
Santa this year, no letter to Santa.
妹妹一人
o}Q老人喝的牛奶、吃的乾
And you made your sister
put out the milk and cookies.
依我看，今年是你的PI年
Sounds to me like
this is your crucial year.
如果我是你
我好好考]要不要上@列火
lf l were you, l would think
about climbing onboard.
戆。快c做Q定
我要到K喔
Come on, come on.
l've got a schedule to keep.
S你便
Suit yourself.
搭北O特快你有好心情
'Cause that's the way things happen
On the Polar Express
琛琛⒒疖快w
那汽笛亮
Whoo, whoo, the whistle blows
That's the sound of her singing
叮、叮、耳
催促我出l
Ding, ding, the bell will ring
Golly, look at her go
不要去多h的地方
都不必心
You wonder if we'll get there soon
Anybody's guess
搭北O特快你有好心情
'Cause that's the way things happen
On the Polar Express
到的r候我_心大叫「耶」
When we get there
We'll scream, ''Yay!''
到的r候跟它一起
迸、迸、迸
We'll arrive with
A bang, bang, bang
琛琛
快废蚯靶
Boom, boom, boom
Laughing all the way
大口吃著美味的食物，高唱著歌
With a comfy seat and lots to eat
Boy, it's just the best
欣p沿途美的好L景
Wish it wouldn't ever have to end
不要去多h的地方
都不必心
With a little luck, we'll be on time
There's no need to stress
搭北O特快你有好心情
'Cause that's the way things happen
On the Polar Express
喂，Γ就是你
你知道@是什N火幔
Hey. Hey, you. Yeah, you.
Do you know what kind of train this is?
@是什N拥幕疖？你知道幔
Train. Do you know what kind of train
this is? Do you?
然知道
Of course.
@是神奇火
lt's a magic train.
-我要去北O
-我然知道@是神奇火
-We're going to the North Pole.
-l know it's a magic train.
它是包德氐诙八四
S三型蒸汽室火^
lt's a Baldwin 2-8-4 S3-class
steam locomotive...
它是一九三一年包德鼗疖工Su造的
重量有四十六f六千一百英磅
...built in 1 931 at the Baldwin Locomotive
Works. lt weighs 456,1 00 pounds and....
我真的要到北O去幔
Are we really going to the North Pole?
-喂，你大家快看！
-真好，不是幔
-Hey, look!
-lsn't that wonderful?
是R波雪！
是R波雪耶！
Herpolsheimer's! Herpolsheimer's!
哇，你看那些Y物，我全都好想要
Wow, look at all those presents.
l want all of them.
好有}Q的感X，好美，好剀班
lt's so Christmassy and cozy
and beautiful!
查票
Tickets.
把票拿出
Tickets, please.
查票
Tickets.
Ticket, please.
翻翻口袋
Try your pocket.
另一K也翻翻看
Try your other pocket.
（北O特快
砘仄保
xx你
Thank you, sir.
嘿，小心一c
Hey, watch out, there.
xx你，先生
Thank you, sir.
@是V播C
不是玩具，不可以S便玩喔
That is a public-address microphone.
lt is not a toy.
那砘镎郜F他剪票的技g
Boy, that guy sure likes to show off.
你看他把我的票剪成@
Look what that wise guy
punched on my ticket.
-@是什N意思啊？
-下一站，厄德布克大道11344
''L-E.'' What the heck does that mean?
-Next stop, 1 1 344 Edbrooke.
你看，火要停下砹艘
We're heading for the other side
of the tracks.
你要搭幔
Well? You coming?
哎，又一搭的
lt's just another pickup.
真怪耶，我以槟闶亲钺嵋了
That's weird. l thought you were
supposed to be the last one.
那用f，然是去北O啊
Why, to the North Pole, of course.
@列就是北O特快啊
This is the Polar Express.
S便你
Suit yourself.
cK喂，他想上耶
Hey, that kid wants
to get on the train.
加油！
Come on!
跑快c！
Hurry up!
我要快想k法停
We have to stop the train.
-我不知道要怎N停K
-拉o急x啊
-l don't know how.
-Pull the emergency brake!
是l拉o急x的！？
Who in the blazes applied
that emergency brake?!
是他
He did.
你？
You.
你最好o我住
那拉K是在o急r的r候用的
ln case you didn't know, that cord
is for emergency purposes only.
有你最好搞清楚
今晚可是}Q夜
And in case you weren't aware,
tonight is Christmas Eve.
@列火的行程非常非常的s
And in case you hadn't noticed,
this train is on a very tight schedule.
好，小朋友
δ承┤碚f，}Q或S不太重要K
Now, young man, Christmas
may not be important to some people...
不^ξ其他人碚f
它可是非常的重要！
...but it is very important
to the rest of us!
可是，可是我K我K
But-- But--
他只是想停下火那人上
He was just trying to stop the train
so that kid could get on.
@影。小朋友
真的是@樱
l see. Young man,
is that what happened?
嗯K
Well....
我提醒你，我的行程非常非常s
Let me remind you we are
on a very tight schedule.
有，我矶]有`c^
And l've never been late before...
我今天晚上也^Σt到，懂幔
...and l am certainly not
going to be late tonight.
好、大家注意，回座位坐好，快c
Now, everybody, take your seats, please!
xx
Thank you.
各位注意
Your attention, please.
有哪位北O特快上的旅客
需要我提供餐c服眨
Are there any Polar Express passengers
in need of refreshment?
-我K我K
-我就知道
-Me! Me! Me!
-l thought so.
-C、C
-喔，]}
-Hot, hot
-Oh, we got it
-C、C
-嘿，]}
-Hot, hot
-Hey, we got it
-C、C
-]}
-Hot, hot
-Say, we got it
崆煽肆ΓC、C
Hot chocolate
Hot, hot
-喔，]}
-C、C
-Oh, we got it
-Hot, hot
-是，]}
-C、C
-So we got it
-Hot, hot
^]}
Yo, we got it
-崆煽闪
-我只有一定K
-Hot chocolate
-Here we've only got one rule
保C他岷艉
Never, ever let it cool
在N房Y我最大
Keep it cooking in the pot
-上桌吧
-崆煽肆
-Then you got
-Hot chocolate
-C、C
-喔，]}
-Hot, hot
-Oh, we got it
-C、C
-嘿，]}
-Hot, hot
-Hey, we got it
-C、C
-]}
-Hot, hot
-Say, we got it
-崆煽肆
-C、C
Hot chocolate
Hot, hot
-喔，]}
-C、C
-Oh, we got it
-Hot, hot
-是，]}
-C、C
-So we got it
-Hot, hot
^]}
Yo, we got it
-崆煽肆
-我只有一定K
-Hot chocolate
-Here we only got one rule
我只有一定K
Here we only got one rule
保C他岷艉
Never, ever let it cool
在N房Y我最大
Keep it cooking in the pot
崆煽肆R上砝
Soon you got hot chocolate
-C、C
-嘿，]}
-Hot, hot
-Hey, we got it
-C、C
-我]}
-Hot, hot
-Oh, we got it
-C、C
-呀，]}
-Hot, hot
-Yeah, we got it
-C、C
-我]有}
-Hot, hot
-Oh, we got it
-C、C
-呀，]}
-Hot, hot
-Yeah, we got it
-我]有}
-C、C
-Oh, we got it
-Hot, hot
呀，]}
Yeah, we got it
那鞍。阿斯帝卡王朝的王孟特儒
You know, Montezuma,
the king of the Aztecs...
每天都要喝差不多五十公升的崆煽肆
...would drink 50 quarts
of hot chocolate every day.
獾南泥巴一蛹t
因樗在Y面加了t辣椒，不是糖喔
lt was thick as mud and red.
He put chili pepper in instead of sugar.
-所以是「辣」巧克力眩
-你又知道，我才不信咧
-Get it? Hot chocolate?
-How do you know? That's not true.
-你要拿去哪Y呀？
-拿o他呀
-Where you going with that?
-lt's for him.
-我不是不能S便x_座位幔
-]e，@邮沁`反F路交通t
-l don't think we're to leave our seats.
-lt's a violation of safety regulations...
]有大人陪伴，小孩不能在Yy跑
...for a kid to cross moving cars
without a grown-up.
我想]}
l think l'll be okay.
你_定幔
Are you sure?
在後的那小朋友
他有]有喝到崆煽肆Π。
What about this lad in the back?
Did he get any refreshment?
那我就分一co他嘛
Well, let's take some to him,
by all means.
看好路，小心走
Watch your step, now. Watch your step.
她忘了拿票
She forgot her ticket.
]有剪^耶
lt hasn't been punched.
喂，你想做什N？你害我倒大楣啦
What are you doing?
You're gonna get us in trouble!
小妹妹，不好意思
Young lady, forgive me.
我好像]有剪^你的票喔
l believe l have neglected
to punch your ticket.
麻┠悖
May l?
我把票放在座位上K
l left my ticket right here on the seat.
-可是不了
-你是fK
-But it's gone.
-You mean...
你把你的票K弄G了？
...you have lost your ticket.
弄G票的不是她
She didn't lose her ticket.
是我
l did.
我本硐氚衍票拿去o你
l was trying to return it to you.
可是不小心被L吹走了
But the wind blew it out of my hand.
我的o你好了
You can have my ticket.
@些票是不可以S便交Q的
These tickets are not transferable.
小妹妹
Young lady...
麻┠愀我硪幌
...you will just have to
come along with me.
你知道他把她怎N幔
他把她扔下火
You know what's gonna happen now?
He's gonna throw her off the train.
Γ搞不好У阶钺嵋还扔下去
He's gonna probably throw her
off the rear platform.
@是食绦
那铀才不被卡在下面
Standard procedure. That way,
she won't get sucked under the wheels.
他也S把火p速
但是^Σ停下
They may slow the train down,
but they're never gonna stop it.
停下恚
Stop it?
f的Γ∥揖妥火再停一次
That's it! l have to stop the train again.
你不要再[了啦
No, please, don't do that again.
他在哪？
Where'd they go?
他怎N了？
What happened to them?
那女生有麻┝耍你一定要臀野
Please, she's in big trouble.
You have to help me.
嘿！
Hey!
我找到你的票了！等一下！
l found your ticket! Wait!
嘿！
Hey!
等一下！
Wait!
我找到票了！
l have your ticket!
要不要我湍忝Π。
ls there something l can do for you?
我在找一K女生
l'm looking for a girl.
一女K
A gi--?
我不都是幔
Ain't we all?
@是她的票
l have her ticket.
哦？o我看看，我看看@到底是什N？
Well, lookie. Lookie here. What is this?
@可是一真的火票，如假包Q喔
This is an official, authentic,
genuine ticket to ride.
嗯K你最好把票
藏到安全的地方，小朋友
You better keep this
in a safe place, young man.
如果我是你K
lf l was you....
我把所有值X的家K放在@
l keep all my valuables right here.
十三破鞋Y^
Right here in the old size 1 3.
告V我，藏在@鹤畋ｋU了
Experience shows
this is the safest place.
不^那|西我是不常用啦
Not that l have much use for those.
票？
Tickets.
我都坐霸王
l ride for free.
真的，我想坐的r候
我只要跳上去就行了
Oh, yeah, yeah. l hop aboard this rattler
any time l feels like it.
@w我管，
l own this train. Oh, yeah.
我就像是列之王一
北O特快之王
lt's like l'm the king of this train.
Yeah. The king of the Pol Ex.
事上，我就是那ゴ蟮谋O之王
ln fact, l am the king
of the North Pole!
忘了招呼你，坐啊，坐坐坐
Oh, where's my manners? Sit, sit. Sit.
e哪N客猓坐下
Take a load off.
要不要睃c咖啡？
Hey, would you like some Joe?
狎vv的咖啡，在冬天夜晚喝最棒了
Nice hot refreshment.
Perfect for a cold winter's night.
喂，小心c
There. Bless you.
那}Q老人呢？
What about Santa?
-}Q老人？
-}Q老人不是北O之王幔
-Santa?
-lsn't he the king of the North Pole?
你是fK@砘锇。
You mean this guy?
那你心Yδ砘
又是怎N想的呢？
What exactly is your persuasion
on the big man?
既然你提到了K
Since you brought him up.
cK我K
Well, l....
我是很想相信K
l want to believe.
-可是我K
-可是你不想傻傻的被_
-But--
-But you don't wanna be bamboozled.
你不希望到最後你的幻想破
You don't wanna be
led down the primrose path.
你不想被人愚弄，被人耍
也不想像瞎子一颖换Ｅ
You don't wanna be conned or duped,
have the wool pulled over your eyes.
更不想渭的硪惶嘶疖之旅
Hoodwinked. You don't wanna be
taken for a ride, railroaded.
眼{
Seeing is believing.
ΣΓ
Am l right?
那@列火怎Nf？
But what about this train?
什N怎Nf？
What about it?
我全部都要到北O去？
We're all really going
to the North Pole...
ΣΓ
...aren't we?
你f呢？
Aren't we?
你的意思是K
@一切只是一簦
Are you saying
that this is all just a dream?
是你f的喔，小鬼
我可]f
You said it, kid. Not me.
好了，我快去找那女孩吧
So let's go find that girl.
我再你
One other thing.
你相信世上有鬼幔
Do you believe in ghosts?
有意思
lnteresting.
等等
Wait.
等等！
Wait!
我要快c醒
l have to wake up.
Γ我要快c醒
Yeah. l have to wake up.
嗯K醒硇研选⑿
Wake up. Wake up. Wake up.
嗯K醒醒
Wake up!
小鬼！小鬼！
Kid!
小鬼，你少在那Y作袅
Kid, get your head out of the clouds!
快醒一醒呀，小鬼
Wake up, kid!
在北O特快上面可是不准暨[的喔
There's no sleepwalking
on the Polar Express.
戆伞⑽要跳了
We gotta jump them knuckles.
快啊，小鬼，坐到我肩膀上
Come on, kid. Flip my shoulders.
手o我
Grab my lily.
你找的那R子一定是跑到前面去了
That skirt you're chasing
must have moved ahead.
-我得卯起硇n去叭叭卜卜那Y
-什N叭叭卜卜那Y？
-We gotta hightail it to the hog, pronto.
-To the hog?
引擎室，火的引擎室，菜B
The engine. The engine, you tenderfoot.
我得加把
要在到平隧道前s到
We gotta make the engine
before we hit Flat Top Tunnel.
椤K槭颤N？
How come?
你}真多啊
So many questions.
因檫@列火的
跟平隧道的高度K
There is but one inch of clearance
between the roof of this rattler...
只差了一英
...and the roof of Flat Top Tunnel.
懂幔
Savvy?
火_始爬坡了
lt's just the run up to the hump, kid.
@很刺激唷
This will be interesting.
快c爬上戆。小鬼
Get back on, kid. Hurry!
抓住我的滑U
Grab my muck stick.
想跳^去只有一碎[
There's only one trick to this, kid.
我一f「跳」K
When l say ''jump'' ...
你就跳！
...you jump!
是你？我以槟惚蝗酉氯チ四亍K
You. l thought you got thrown off, and--
-槭颤N是你在_火啊？
-是他叫我_的啊
-You're driving the train?
-They put me in charge.
-火司C去修袅
-襞菰谶@，小心c
-The engineer had to check the light.
-Here's the light. Careful.
好，o我
All right, now.
我砟
l got it.
-你怎N操作？
-危恚我斫棠
-How do you know how?
-lt's easy. Come here, l'll show you.
@大大的|西就是忾y
This big lever here, that's the throttle.
@小的呢，就是x
This little one here, that's the brake.
有，那些是毫忾y
And those are the pressure gauges.
那lK子K就是獾
And that rope is the whistle.
是獾眩
The whistle.
要不要？
You wanna try it?
我想拉獾严牒镁昧
l've wanted to do that my whole life.
住，住呀
Hold still! Hold still! Don't move!
你看K
Look!
停！快停！
Stop the train! Stop the train!
Stop the train!
什N？
What?
他要我停
They want us to stop the train.
-哪一是x呀？
-他跟我f是@
-Which one is the brake?
-He told me this was.
-l？
-火司Cf的
-Who?
-The engineer.
-火司C？可是@才比^像是x
-不Γ他f@才是
-The engineer? This one looks like a brake.
-No, he said this was the brake.
你_定幔
Are you sure?
你_不_定啊？
拉x啊
Pull the brake!
快c停！
Stop the train!
北美Z鹿？
Caribou?
如果我不能r到_
}Q就泡了
There can be no Christmas without
the Polar Express arriving on time.
怎N搞的？
y道只有我一人在心啊？
Am l the only one who understands that?
是你，我就知道
You. l should have known.
小子，你根本就不想
@列火_到北OΣΓ
Are you bound and determined that
this train never reaches the North Pole?
你看
But look.
Z鹿^平交道？
Caribou crossing?!
我猜那群鹿至少有十fb
搞不好有一百fb呢
l make that herd to be at least
1 00,000, maybe even a million.
那得等上好小r
他才能通通走_
lt's gonna be hours
before they clear this track.
-真是人X筋啊
-我看@下子我麻┛纱罅
-A tough nut to crack.
-We are in some serious jelly.
-真棘手啊
-事情大l
-And a jam.
-Tight spot.
-]救
-死定
-Up a creek.
-Up a tree.
-坐著等死吧
-我告V你什N是等死K
-Lost in the grass.
-l'll tell you what's grass: our a--
搞定了
^m慢速前M
Problem solved. All ahead, slow.
速度不太快了啊？
We're going pretty fast.
去告V火司C
_慢一c
Tell the engineer to slow down.
Slow it down.
速度太快了！
Watch the speed!
糗了，_口N_，掉下砹
Jumping jeepers,
the cotter pin sheared off.
-什N？
-_口N
-What?
-The pin.
-在哪Y啊？
-在那Y
-Where?
-There.
-啊，糟了
-Oh, no.
-他不耶
-不？
-They can't hear me.
-They can't?
（危U，179度U降坡
用低速n）
又有r了
快，站到把手诟诉@
l don't like the look of this.
Under the safety bar.
我K我不有事吧？
F在怎Nk？
ls everything all right?
What should we do?
照目前的情r砜
我跟火司C的通已中嗔
Considering we've lost communication
with the engineer...
而我三人被困在火^的外面
哪阂踩ゲ涣
...we are standing totally exposed
on the front of the locomotive...
火跑的速度越碓娇
快到]有k法控制
...the train appears to be
accelerating uncontrollably...
我F在正w快的Kn向K
著名的冰河{谷
...and we are rapidly
approaching Glacier Gulch...
那Y好是地球上最陡的坡
...which happens to be the steepest
downhill grade in the world...
我建h大家最好K
...l suggest we all hold on...
抓o一cK
...tightly.
-_口N
-The pin.
死定了，前面的F上全都Y了冰啊
Jiminy Christmas, the ice has frozen
over the tracks.
抓了
Hold on. Hold on. No, no.
小心c，站了
Come on. Watch your step.
快上恚快上
Come on, sweetie.
Up you go. Up you go.
踩@Y，@Y
Put your feet on here. On here.
有c冒U喔
Little adventure, huh?
小子，你X筋D的M快的
Young man, quick thinking on your part.
站到左去
快c站^去
Step to your left, please. To your left.
嗯，@幼雍枚嗔
Well, that is more like it.
你到底搞什N鬼啊？
What in the name of Mike?
你看
Look.
火屁股了，快走呀！
Get us the blazes out of here!
快c把火掉^
Turn this sled around.
你看那Y
Look there.
道在K
Tracks.
正前方
Dead ahead.
往右
Right.
往左
Left.
往右
Right.
往左D
Hang a Louie.
再往右D
Toss a Ritchie.
舵向左
Port astern.
全速前M往右
To the starboard.
-啊，我的鞋
-你的票快掉了
-My slipper.
-You're gonna lose your ticket.
那不是我的，是你的
lt's not my ticket, it's yours.
-我的票？
-
-lt's my ticket?
-Yes.
右，要跟上，左
Right. Keep up with me. Left.
右、左
Right. Left.
右
Right.
左
Left.
右
Right.
左、右
Left. Right.
-啊，糟了
-Oh, no!
抓好了！
Brace yourselves!
@才像嘛
Well, that's more like it.
xx你
Thank you.
]想到你臀艺一亓塑票
Thank you. l can't believe
you found my ticket.
是不是有人f「找」回了票？
Did someone say they found a ticket?
如果是的K
麻┠悖票o我
Well, in that case.... Tickets, please.
xx
Thank you.
-@是什N？
-嘿，跟那戴眼R的一
-''L-E''?
-Just like that know-it-all kid.
小心c，看好再走
Watch your step.
Tricky walking up here.
@上面不好走，很容易滑倒
lt's mighty slick.
Mighty slick, l tell you.
你看吧，我不是f^了，@Y很滑幔
There you go. What did l tell you?
多年前，我第一次在}Q夜值班
我爬到上巡K
Years ago, on my first Christmas Eve run,
l was up on the roof making my rounds...
不小心踩到冰K滑了一下
...when l slipped on the ice myself.
我手抓了一把手
Y果把手嗔耍我摔了一大跤
l reached out for a hand iron,
but it broke off. l slid and fell.
不^好K我福大命大、]有摔下火
And yet, l did not fall off this train.
有人救了你？
Someone saved you?
是有|西救了我
Or something.
是天使？
An angel.
也S喔
Maybe.
等等，等等
Wait. Wait.
他K他L得什N幼樱你看了幔
What did he look like? Did you see him?
]看，m然有r候眼{K
No, sir. But sometimes
seeing is believing.
但有的r候，那些最真的事情
s是看不的
And sometimes the most real things
in the world are the things we can't see.
啊，被人、z忘的一群
The forsaken and the abandoned.
小心e踩到他
@些可z的玩具，任人糟蹋蛄
Mind your step, now.
These poor toys have suffered enough...
被扔到黑暗空的角落Y
等著腐生P
...being left to rust and decay in the
back alleys and vacant lots of the world.
-他怎N在@Y啊？
-@是一老想出淼狞c子
-What are they doing here?
-lt's a new concept the boss came up with.
不把他G掉
而是把他收集起恚重新改b
lnstead of being thrown away,
they're collected. Refurbished.
他f@叫做K玩具回收吧
He calls it ''rebicycling.''
Something like that.
看得我好想哭喔
Makes me wanna cry...
@些玩具竟然被@釉闾
...seeing toys that were
treated this way.
那些被打了死Y
p得y七八糟的木偶和娃娃K
These hopelessly entangled
string puppets and marionettes...
是最y修理的
我lF手指`巧的北O工匠FK
...pose a particular problem. We found
the nimble fingers of our work force...
是最修理那些p得y七八糟
和打著死Y的木偶跟娃娃的
...here at the North Pole are best
for working out those knots and tangles.
xx，喔，i得死死的
Thank you. Double-locked here.
@位小朋友，你跟我一模一印K
You are just like me, my friend.
什N都不信！
A scrooge!
小夤恚史扒皮
Ebenezer Scrooge.
什N北O、}Q老人、特快
North Pole, Santa Claus, this train...
根本都是人家在胡f八道
真是人倒足了胃口
...it's all a bunch of humbug.
A bout of indigestion.
啊，Γ我知道你是怎N想的
Oh, yeah. l know what you are.
反正你就是不信！
You're a doubter.
就是不信！
A doubter. You don't believe!
就是不信！就是不信！
You're a doubter! You don't believe!
你都]看到
我碾U降坡上面n下
You missed it.
We rode down some really sharp hills.
然後又到了一像冰湖的地方
不^我想那是月光跟大釉斐傻幕糜
We were on what looked like a frozen lake.
But l know it was just an optical illusion.
他f火行在冰由
但是我f@怎N可能？
He said the train was on ice.
l said it's impossible--
火怎N可能x_FK
喂，你又要去哪？
You can't put a train track--
Where you going now?
我χ星星S
I'm wishing on a star
著相信
And trying to believe
m然路途bh
That even though it's far
他在}Q夜找到我
He'll find me Christmas Eve
我猜}Q老公公很忙
I guess that Santa's busy
他]磉^
'Cause he's never come around
}Q砼Rr
我就想起他
I think of him
When Christmas comes to town
每年最好的日子
The best time of the year
是大家FAr
When everyone comes home
}Q夥
With all this Christmas cheer
我不再孤
It's hard to be alone
跟朋友一起
阎媚敲利的}Q
Putting up the Christmas tree
With friends who come around
}Q砼Rr
就是我美好的r光
It's so much fun
When Christmas comes to town
o孩子的Y物
色ttGG
Presents for the children
Wrapped in red and green
那些我^s]看^的|西
All the things I've heard about
But never really seen
]有人沉睡
No one will be sleeping
度^著@}Q夜晚
On the night of Christmas Eve
希望}Q老人已上路
Hoping Santa's on his way
}Q起
When Santa's sleighbells ring
我注意的
I listen all around
天使R歌唱
The herald angels sing
我什N都不到
I never hear a sound
孩子的粝
And all the dreams of children
都被F
Once lost will all be found
}Q夜我想要的就@N多
That's all I want
When Christmas comes to town
}Q夜我想要的就@N多
That's all I want
When Christmas comes to town
你看
Look.
是北O光
The northern lights.
嘿，你三
Hey. You three.
我^了K
We just crossed it.
北六十六度，M入了北O圈
Latitude 66'33' .
The Arctic Circle.
看到了幔
hh的地方不是有一些光幔
And do you see?
Those lights in the distance.
那些光看起砭拖袷
航行在冰海上的h洋渡
They look like the lights of a strange
ocean liner sailing on a frozen sea.
那YK
There...
就是北O了
...is the North Pole.
像那神奇的魔毯聿恍菹
It's a magic carpet on a rail
It never takes a rest
你穿越重重的山X
Flying through
The mountains and the snow
不要再q豫
快跟著我_心的f「好」
You can ride for free and join the fun
If you just say yes
搭北O特快你有好心情
'Cause that's the way things happen
On the Polar Express
琛琛⒒疖快w
那汽笛亮
Whoo, whoo, the whistle blows
That's the sound of her singing
叮、叮、耳
催促我出l
Ding, ding, the bell will ring
Golly, look at her go
不要去多h的地方
都不必心
You wonder if you'll get there soon
Anybody's guess
搭北O特快你有好心情
'Cause that's the way things happen
On the Polar Express
到的r候我_心大叫「耶」
When we get there
We'll scream, ''Yay!''
到的r候跟它一起
迸、迸、迸
We'll arrive with
A bang, bang, bang
琛琛
快废蚯靶
Boom, boom, boom
Laughing all the way
s上了，我提早了五分呢
We made it. With five minutes to spare.
s上了！
We made it.
有精`啊，怎N]看到？
There should be elves.
Where are the elves?
ρ剑精`在哪？
Yeah, where are the elves?
他在市中心那集合
They are gathering
in the center of the city.
因槁}Q老人在那
送出今年的第一份}QY物
That is where Santa will give
the first gift of Christmas.
l可以拿到第一份Y物？
Who gets the first gift of Christmas?
}Q老人哪中x一
He will choose one of you.
-你看！
-精`！
-Look.
-Elves!
好的，各位先生女士
All right. All right,
ladies and gentlemen.
F在麻┐蠹遗懦膳
Two columns, if you please.
矮的在前面，高的在後面
Shorter in the front, taller in the rear.
出生日期p的麻┱居疫
翁的站左
Even-numbered birthdays on the right,
odd-numbered on the left.
不要D，注意，不要D
我不能t到
No pushing. No pushing.
But let's not dilly-dally.
差五分就要十二c了
lt's five minutes to midnight.
喂，你搞e了
四分前就差五分到十二c了
Hey, what gives? lt was five minutes
till midnight four minutes ago.
一c也]e
排成膳
Exactly. Columns of two.
-一、二
-K
-One, two.
-Excuse me.
-什N事？
-他怎Nk？
-Question.
-What about him?
我不勉e人去}Q老人
No one is required to see Santa.
各位先生女士
你不需要手渴帧K
Ladies and gentlemen,
you do not have to hold hands...
-戆
-不^待何往前走的r候K
-Come on.
-...but please remain in your columns...
麻┐蠹遗藕藐伍
...while we are in transit.
-你一定要跟我去
-她f得
-Look, you have to come with us.
-She's right.
我X得}Q]有意x
根本]有
Christmas just doesn't work out
for me. Never has.
}Q是很棒，很美好的日耶
But Christmas is such a wonderful,
beautiful time.
它我心中充M感恩和P
lt's a time for giving and being thankful,
for friends and family.
家家舳阎寐}Q
}Q老人在}Q湎旅娣哦Y物呢
People hang decorations and lights. Santa
leaves presents under our Christmas trees.
可是我K
Christmas just...
不^}Q的啊
...doesn't work out for me.
我不管}Qδ碚f有]有意x
Look, l don't know if Christmas
is gonna work out for you or not...
但今天是}Q夜
你不要一人留在@Y嘛
...but this is Christmas Eve.
Don't stay here by yourself.
ρ剑跟我砺
Yes, come with us.
我一起去
We'll go together.
啊，糟了
Oh, no.
我不有事的
We're gonna be okay.
我e了K
Maybe not!
o急x在哪？
The emergency brake.
o急x呢？
我找不到o急x！
There's no brake. l can't find the brake!
找什Nx嘛，小鬼
Take a break, kid.
要不要肀狎vv的香饪Х龋
How about a nice, good hot cup of Joe?
要撞了！
We're gonna crash!
我在打D
We're spinning.
]？
You hear that?
K
The bell.
-什N啊？
-雪橇的K啊
-What bell?
-The sleighbell.
-K？
-你]到幔
-Sleighbell?
-Don't you hear it?
是乃淼姥Y鞒淼
lt's coming from that tunnel.
我往那走
That's the way we should go.
快戆
Come on.
致铮
What?
-怎N了？
-走吧
-What?
-Come on.
快c
Come on.
我迷路了
We're lost.
（包b中心，甜c店）
Yes.
-]e，我到了
-我也到了
-Yes. l hear it.
-l hear it too.
-我什N也]到
-好，往@走
-l don't hear anything.
-Okay, it's down this way.
你_定幔
Are you sure?
非常_定
Absolutely.
那槭颤N我都]到？
Why can't l hear anything?
蹲下恚小c
Get down and be quiet.
什N？
Yeah.
好的
Okay.
老大，是包b中心打淼
Well, that was the wrapping hall, chief.
-他包完最後一份Y物
-他用什N包？
-Just finished the last one.
-How's it wrapped?
t白ly的包b
上面了漂亮的G色蝴蝶Y
lt's wrapped in candy-striped red
with a number-seven holly-green bow.
蝴蝶Y？
他不知道我就快聿患傲幔
A number-seven bow?
When we're this close to liftoff?
他到底在想些什N？
他啦？
What are they thinking down there?
Are they meshuggener?
-要送去哪Y？
-要送去美
-What's the routing?
-Going to the States.
密西根州的大激流城
Grand Rapids, Michigan.
是我的家l耶
That's my town. l'm from Grand Rapids.
（{皮）
又出F一v蛋{皮鬼了
x@rg狒[
We got a troublemaker now.
Just what we need.
嫌事情不y呀？
查一查他在哪
Things aren't bad enough.
What's his 20?
查到了
他住在~晌髀波滏
Apparently, some kid
from Maplewood, New Jersey...
他把口香糖黏在妹妹的^上
...stuck some gum in his sister's hair.
~晌鳎渴遣皇侨ツ臧D放在K
New Jersey? ls that the same kid
that put the tack...
-老椅|底下的那男生？
-不是，@小鬼的名字叫史蒂芬
-...underneath his teacher's chair last year?
-No, sir. This kid's name is Steven.
老大，怎N理？
要向老公公f幔
So, what do we do, chief?
Alert the big man?
P他、今年不送他}QY物呀？
We talking nothing for Christmas here?
我真的]有黏
I didn't do it.
R上就要^}Q了嘛
Look, it's....
lt's almost Christmas, huh?
就放那小鬼一R吧
We'll cut the kid a break.
不^，把他列入明年送Y物的}查名
But put him on the check-twice list
for next year.
好了，各位
All right, boys.
Y物名胃愣
今年就送@些Y物，出l
Let's shut it down.
That's it for this year. Come on.
-老大，要坐榆幔
-然要坐榆K
-Hey, boss, are we taking the pneumatic?
-Of course we're taking the pneumatic.
只有@游才能r抵_V
lt's the only way to get
to the square on time.
-我走吧
-rg就是金X
-Let's go.
-And time is money.
洌上
Ready, and mount.
好，PT
Good. Close.
好，上戆
All right, get in.
@雍幔
l don't know about this.
我]到音，你呢？
l don't hear it. Do you?
]有
No.
我想我沿箭^走
l think we should follow those arrows.
有出口才ρ
l thought there'd be a way out.
看不到c祝典Y了啦
We're gonna miss everything.
喂，你看
Hey, look.
是Y物
A present.
要送去我家l
o一叫比利的
lt's going to my town.
To someone named Billy.
-我就叫比利
-地址是厄德布克大道11344
-My name is Billy.
-lt's going to 1 1 344 Edbrooke Avenue.
那是我家地址
That's my address.
快戆
Come on.
快看
Look.
上面著
「}Q快罚比利，}Q老人上」
lt says, ''Merry Christmas, Billy.
From Mr. C.''
我知道@Y面是什N
我一直好想要@|西
l think l know what it is.
l wanted one of these my whole life.
等等、等等，e拆，你看
Wait, wait. Stop. Look.
（}Q前，勿拆_）
可是K我K
But l....
@是定喔
Those are the rules.
有|西抓住我
Something's got me.
它抓著我的_
lt's got my leg.
我拉不影
l can't hold him.
那b手o我
快把那b手o我
Give me your other hand.
-我不要
-我档饺
-l can't.
-On three.
一、二、三
One, two, three.
-你看
-它抓著我
-Look.
-lt's still got me.
再狄淮危一、二、三
On three again. One, two, three.
-是你？
-You.
-你在@Y做什N？
-跟你一
-What are you doing here?
-Same as you.
z查我的}QY物啊
看我要的是不是每佣加
Checking my presents. Making sure
l'm getting everything on my list.
不^我只找到一佣Y物
Y面b的全都是好h的纫
l found one present.
All it had was stupid underwear.
你看
Look.
Sr可以降落
You may start your descent
any time now.
如果各位已浜昧说脑
At your convenience, of course.
喂，只剩五分了，我淼眉鞍
lt's still five to.
l think we're gonna make it.
然淼眉埃x十二c有五分耶
我rg多的很
Of course. lt's been five to
for the last hour.
我F在什N都]有，就是有rg
We got plenty of time. We got nothing
but time. We got time to kill.
我X得我到不了
You know what?
l don't think we're gonna make it.
也S我只是F路局的老列L
l may be just an old railroader...
於p巧的w行船也一o所知
...and know nothing about
lighter-than-air craft...
不^在我@外行人看
你要再w高一c比^好
...but from my layman's perspective,
you need more altitude!
再w高一c
More altitude!
注意高度，w高一c
Altitude, please. A bit more altitude, please.
浣德洌
Geronimo!
他是w行精`
The Flying Elves.
他都是＜
可e自己在家偷W喔
They are specialists.
Do not try that at home, kids.
千fe自己在家偷
Do not try that at home.
我^不去的
We're not gonna make it.
真是良好啊
A well-oiled machine.
好了，你@搭便的
All right, you stowaways.
-玩完了吧
-我只是跟他走喔
-Party's over.
-l was just following them.
我是不小心掉M淼
We fell in here by mistake.
算了
我一直都知道你躲在@Y
Forget about it. We knew you
was in there the whole time.
好了，快c出戆
Come on, out you go.
Α⒊幼骺欤幼骺
Let's go, come on.
Step up, step up. There we go.
]什N好怕的，戆
Not a problem. Come on.
Watch your step. There you go.
我用@方法把你放下去
就不有人受了
So nobody gets hurt, here's
how we're gonna get you guys down.
-@N危我然知道K
-Γ你什N都知道
-This is simple. Why, l know--
-What do you know?
那你知不知道
你根本就不在@Y啊？
You're not supposed to be here
in the first place.
不^今天是}Q
那我就放你一R
But since it's Christmas,
l'm gonna let you slide.
嘿
Hey.
我正在找你呢
Been looking for you.
There you go.
好，恚小心c
Watch your step.
小心c
Careful.
姿萃γ赖泥
Beautiful form. Beautiful.
g迎再度w
Nice to see you again.
淼脑绮蝗淼那桑是幔
Cutting it kind of close, aren't we?
怼K@先交o我
l'll take care of this.
我小心保管
lt's in good hands.
相信我
Trust me.
@就是佳的精神
It's the spirit of the season
四充M著喜
You can feel it in the air
只要你仔的聆
You can hear it if you listen
人人都互相P心
Everywhere
So much care
\心在祈\
Like a prayer
和我一起分享
}Qg返夥
Whatever it is
You need to share it
@就是佳的精神
It's the spirit of the season
四充M著喜
You can feel it in the air
那些K真好，不是幔
Aren't those bells
the most beautiful sound?
他砹耍∷砹耍
He's here! He's here!
在哪Y？
Where?
我看了，他在那Y
l see him. He's over there.
我]看呀
l can't see him.
我看不到他！
我]看他啊！
l can't see him!
就是不信K
Doubter. Doubter.
好吧
Okay.
我相信
l believe.
我K相信
你f什N？
What was that you said?
我K我相信
l-- l believe.
我相信
l believe.
我K我相信@是你的|西
l-- l believe that this is yours.
嗯K
Well....
xx你
Thank you.
我！我！x我，}Q老人！
-Me, me. Pick me, Santa.
-What are you doing? Stop it.
-x我，}Q老人
-u，你在做什N？不要吵
-Pick me, pick me. l want the first gift.
-Hush.
小朋友
Young man...
要有耐心
...patience.
有Kt一c
@δ惚容^好喔
And a smidgen of humility
might also serve you well.
知道了
Yes, sir.
有你，小妹妹
And you, young lady....
果唷⒂凶孕
A lady of decision.
全身都充M了活力、神采wP
Full of confidence and spirit.
很有}Q精神
Christmas spirit.
要^m保持喔
Keep up the good work.
xx
Thank you.
有比利
And Billy.
你叫比利吧？
lt is Billy?
看砟憬涣瞬簧傩屡笥
l see you've made some new friends.
是啊，好多新朋友
Yes, sir. l sure have.
你很幸\喔
That's a lucky lad.
友x就是最棒的Y物
There's no greater gift than friendship.
至於今年的第一份Y物K
And speaking of gifts...
我Q定送o@位小朋友
...let's have this young fellow
right here.
f吧K
Now...
你想要什N}QY物呀？
...what would you like for Christmas?
我？
Me.
ρ
You.
Yes. lndeed.
可以，然可以
Yes, indeed.
送出第一份}QY物樱
The first gift of Christmas!
@K跟我一樱能代表K
This bell is a wonderful symbol
of the spirit of Christmas...
}Q的精神
...as am l.
要住喔
Just remember...
其}Q的真客
...the true spirit of Christmas...
就在你的心Y
...lies in your heart.
}Q快
Merry Christmas.
你最好把@Y物收好
Better keep that in a safe place.
（`c，r，早到
可能聿患埃
哇塞，你\庹婧
Hey, hey. Man alive, are you lucky.
戆桑小Z鹿，出l印K
Pull, Comet. Pull, boy!
跑啊！跑快一c喔
Prancer, that's a girl.
戆桑穿越天H
Good boy, Donder.
好乖，再跑快一c
我的指]，成一直，小Z鹿
Now, Dasher. Now, Prancer and Vixen.
跟我想像中的一模一右
lt's everything l dreamed it would be.
我K
Could all--?
不只是在作舭。
Could all this be nothing but a dream?
不是
No.
跳上高高的屋，穿^重重的
To the top of the roof
To the top of the wall
我去送Y物去吧
出l樱快c，我出l樱
Now, dash away, dash away
Dash away all
上樱
All aboard!
一、二、一、二、三，戆桑
One, two. One, two, three, go.
Rockin' on top of the world
The place is hoppin'
There ain't no stoppin'
Rockin' on top of the world
Lift your spirits, swing that girl
Tonight, yeah
Come on, shorty!
把票浜茫xx
Show your tickets.
Have your tickets ready.
得要z取五大食物喔
Remember to eat
the five basic food groups.
麻┸票，xx
Ticket, please.
得後一定要刷牙喔
And please brush after every meal.
^R路前，要先左右看一看喔
Remember to duck and cover.
xx你，麻，票
All right, you. Ticket, please.
@英文是什N意思啊？
''Lean.'' Whatever that's
supposed to mean.
你看到的是四字母
''Lean'' is spelled with four letters.
我打了五字母
l believed l punched five.
（I悟）
嘿，你是f我看不懂K
Hey, are you saying
l don't know how to--?
喔，Σ黄
是「I悟」  ，我看e了
l'm sorry. lt says ''learn.'' My mistake.
I悟到教了
Lesson learned.
票？
Ticket.
（信）
（信任）
（信心）
@票很特e吧？
That is some special ticket.
就是啊
Sure is.
那K你有]有信心
我可以把你平安送回家呀？
So can you count on us
to get you home safe and sound?
然有
Absolutely.
我K
Me...
跟我的朋友都有
...and my friends.
票
Ticket.
（IВ
IВ槭颤N是「IА鼓兀
lt says ''lead.'' Like ''lead balloon.''
希望@一趟你能有所收
l believe it also is pronounced ''lead.''
I悟到怎NI袖K
As in ''leader,'' ''leadership.''
ьI大家走向正途
''Lead the way.''
我永h追S您
Follow you anywhere, ma'am.
剩你了
Ah, yes.
MX子都是的小朋友
Young man with all the questions.
票
Ticket.
（相信）
上面K
lt says--
不用告V我什N
lt's nothing l need to know.
-K呢？
-借o我看看嘛
-Come on, let's see the bell.
-Let's see it.
-那K呢？
-ρ剑借我看一下嘛
-Come on, let's see the bell.
-Show us the bell.
快c嘛，快c、快c
Yeah, let's see the bell.
不了
lt's gone.
-在哪Y？
-我弄G了
-Where is it?
-l lost it.
一定是掉在}Q老人的雪橇上
l lost the bell from Santa's sleigh.
弄G了？
lt's gone?
e心
Don't worry.
-我想一定找到的
-一定的
-We'll-- We'll find it.
-Yeah, we'll find it.
ρ剑我湍阏遥大家一起找
Yeah, we'll help you. All of us.
好，那我大家快分^去找吧
Yeah, let's hurry out
and find it right now.
聿患傲
lt's too late.
真的太可惜了
Gee, that's really too bad.
真的
Really.
很z憾
l'm sorry.
厄德布克大道11344
1 1 344 Edbrooke.
下一站
厄德布克大道11344
Next stop, 1 1 344 Edbrooke.
喂，你要去哪Y？
Hey, where you going?
回家
Home.
喔，好吧，}Q快
Oh, okay. Merry Christmas.
xx你臀野鸦疖停下
Thanks for stopping the train for me.
祝你}Q快
Have a wonderful Christmas.
小心c、e摔跤
Watch your step, please.
祝你}Q快
And merry Christmas.
你看
Look.
}Q老人已去^比利家了耶
Santa got to Billy's house already.
你看，}Q老人送的！
他磉^了，他磉^了！
Look, look! Santa got here!
好神奇喔
lsn't that amazing?
的_很神奇
lt is amazing.
太不可思h了
K不了，我也很y^
l'm sorry about the bell.
那Y物真的很特e
lt was a really special present.
你也e太y^
Well, you know what they say.
心意收到了就好啦
lt's the thought that counts.
也
Yeah.
那K再了
Well, see you.
嗯K
Well...
再了
...see you.
再
See you.
小心c，看好路再走
Watch your step, please.
xx你
Thank you.
不，xx你
No, thank you.
搭北O特快啊
One thing about trains:
重c不在於去哪
lt doesn't matter where they're going.
而是在於你要不要搭火
What matters is deciding to get on.
}Q快罚
Merry Christmas!
什K什N？
What?
}Q快罚
Merry Christmas!
醒醒，哥哥，醒醒
他磉^了，}Q老人磉^了
Wake up. Wake up.
Santa's been here. Santa's been here.
快恚快砺
Hurry up. Hurry up!
爸爸，
快c醒醒，快c醒醒！
Mom, Dad, wake up. Wake up!
}Q老人磉^了，他磉^了！
Santa's been here! Santa's been here!
爸爸、、你看！
他送了我好多Y物喔
Mom, Dad, look!
He brought us all kinds of stuff!
哇！是火，火耶！
Look, a train!
好棒喔，我矶]有收^
@N棒的}QY物
This is the beautiful-est,
most wonderful-est Christmas ever.
等等，你看
Wait. Look.
有一
Here's one more.
有你的名字耶
Has your name on it.
我在雪橇的座位下lF了@K
Found this on the seat of my sleigh.
最好p一下口袋的破洞喔
Better fix that hole in your pocket.
}Q老人上
Mr. C.
哇，好漂亮的K
l送的呀？
Oh, what a beautiful bell.
Who's it from?
-}Q老人
-}Q老人？
-Santa.
-Santa?
真的啊？
Really?
-噢，真是可惜耶
-什N可惜啊？
-Oh, that's too bad.
-What's this?
嗯？牧税。
Broken.
e太y^啊，鹤
Sorry about that, sport.
快c吧
不然要t到
Come on, kids. We don't wanna be late.
我有很多朋友
小r候都曾^K
At one time, most of my friends
could hear the bell.
但L大後，Ks不再樗起
But as years passed,
it fell silent for all of them.
就B莎拉也哪衬甑穆}Q起
就再也]^K了
Even Sarah found, one Christmas, that she
could no longer hear its sweet sound.
m然我L大了K
Though I've grown old...
但K仍然槲翼起
...the bell still rings for me.
也槊相信的人，美妙的起
As it does for all who truly believe.
а荩毫_勃辛密克斯
。毫_勃辛密克斯
威廉布洛以斯二世
u片：史帝夫史_基
_勃辛密克斯
u片：w瑞哥曼
威廉泰特勒
主演：姆h克斯
片名：北O特快
主演：可芴
主演：Z娜w，彼得斯科拉Y
艾迪迪生
主演：R思莉辛密克斯
史蒂芬泰勒
主演：茱琳芮妮，克Y斯科波拉
查理斯佛R契
o念可芴